Inventory of the Blizzard Family Papers, 1861-1868
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Blizzard Family Papers 1930-19491942-1945
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2007.28
211.00
Correspondence, papers, and a photograph concerning three Franklin, West Virginia brothers who served in the United States military during the Second World War. Collection consists of nearly 200 letters of outgoing correspondence penned by three brothers, Arlie, Arthur, and W. Russell Blizzard to their mother and sisters in Franklin, West Virginia. Most correspondence concerns training, work, and soldier life on military bases in the United States during World War II. Also included is Arlie Blizzard's visit to Japan and Korea in late 1945. Collection also contains a few pre and post-war letters and school papers.
Blizzard, Arlie Raymond, 1909-1966; Blizzard, Arthur Roy, 1918-1992; Blizzard, William Russell, 1912-2000
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from eBay on 04/01/2007.
Biographical Note
Arlie Raymond Blizzard (17 Sept. 1909 - 20 Oct. 1966) of Franklin, West Virginia and son of Granville Harris (1874-1934) and Sarah Jane Dahmer Blizzard, enlisted in the United States Army in 1940. In mid 1942, as First Sergeant, he was assigned to Camp Forrest, Tennessee. In the fall of 1942 he moved to army bases in Maryland, Virginia, and North Carolina. In 1943 he was promoted to the rank of First Lieutenant and was assigned to various bases in the western United States; including bases in Montana, Oregon, and Washington. Throughout 1944 and early 1945 he was stationed in Hawaii. He spent July and August 1945 in the Pacific, part of it at Okinawa, Japan, and later at a base in Korea. As a Captain, in late December 1945 Blizzard was honorably discharged and returned home to West Virginia. Blizzard died at Rockingham, Virginia in 1966.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, papers, and a photograph concerning three Franklin, West Virginia brothers who served in the United States military during the Second World War. Collection consists of nearly 200 letters of outgoing correspondence penned by three brothers, Arlie, Arthur, and W. Russell Blizzard to their mother and sisters in Franklin, West Virginia. Most correspondence concerns training, work, and soldier life on military bases in the United States during World War II. Also included is Arlie Blizzard's visit to Japan and Korea in late 1945. Collection also contains a few pre and post-war letters and school papers.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Certificates; Correspondence; Photographs
Topical Term:
World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Front; World War, 1939-1945.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: Arlie R. Blizzard
- Arlie R. Blizzard, 1935-1947
  - (1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1 item, 1935 (1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 19 items, 1942 (1, 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 22 items, 1943 (1, 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 17 items, 1944 (1, 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 25 items, 1945 (1, 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1 item, circa 1942-1945 (1, 6)
    - Photograph of Arlie Blizzard at Okinawa, Japan, 1 item, 1945 (1, 7)
    - US Army company arm-patch, 1 item, circa 1942-1945 (1, 8)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 3 items, 1947 (1, 9)
  Series 2: Arthur R. and W. Russell Blizzard
- Arthur R. and W. Russell Blizzard, 1930-1946
  - (2)
    - Outgoing correspondence of A. Blizzard, 11 items, 1942 (2, 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence of A. Blizzard, 14 items, 1943 (2)
    - Outgoing correspondence of A. Blizzard, 11 items, 1944 (2, 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence of A. Blizzard, 10 items, 1945 (2, 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence of A. Blizzard, 10 items, 1946-1949 (2, 5)
    - A. Blizzard's Shepherd State Teachers College yearbook, and a Presbyterian Church Kingdom Highways youth organization yearbook, 1939 (2, 6)
    - Outgoing correspondence of W. R. Blizzard, 15 items, 1942 (2, 7)
    - Outgoing correspondence of W. R. Blizzard, 13 items, 1943 (2, 8)
    - Outgoing correspondence of W. R. Blizzard, 17 items, 1944 (2, 9)
    - Outgoing correspondence of W. R. Blizzard, 14 items, 1945 (2, 10)
    - Incoming correspondence of W. R. Blizzard, 1 item, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - High school report card of W. R. Blizzard, 1 item, 1930 (2, 12)
    - Incoming correspondence to the Blizzard family, 3 items, 1942-1945 (2, 13)